<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Deep Learning | Turcan Tuna</title>
    <link>https://tutunarsl.github.io/tag/deep-learning/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://tutunarsl.github.io/tag/deep-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Deep Learning</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://tutunarsl.github.io/media/icon_hufdc779f4ff2ddce7bfa0f8235053833b_13200_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Deep Learning</title>
      <link>https://tutunarsl.github.io/tag/deep-learning/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gaussian Process Regression for Groundwater Pollution Prediction</title>
      <link>https://tutunarsl.github.io/project/eth-pai-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tutunarsl.github.io/project/eth-pai-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;description&#34;&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The objective of the project is to predict groundwater pollution levels. To address the computational complexity associated with Gaussian Process models due to the large dataset, the Nyström approximation of the kernel function and inducing points method are applied. The kernel type and hyperparameters are tuned and learned during training. To handle the asymmetric cost, the prior mean is set to a non-trivial value. In this way, the possibility of underestimating the pollution value is reduced when there is large uncertainty about the prediction.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hyperparameter Tuning with Constrained Bayesian Optimization</title>
      <link>https://tutunarsl.github.io/project/eth-pai-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tutunarsl.github.io/project/eth-pai-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;description&#34;&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The objective of the project is to determine the value of a model hyperparameter that maximizes the validation accuracy subject to a constraint on the average prediction speed. To this end, Bayesian Optimization with Expected Improvement (EI) and Upper Confidence Bound (UCB) acquisition functions are employed to implement the algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predicting Uncertainty with Bayesian Neural Networks on MNIST Dataset</title>
      <link>https://tutunarsl.github.io/project/eth-pai-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tutunarsl.github.io/project/eth-pai-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;description&#34;&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The objective of the project is class predictions with uncertainty with an implementation of a Bayesian Neural Network, trained and tested on the Rotated MNIST and Fashion MNIST datasets. The training process minimizes a loss function that considers both a Cross-Entropy loss and a Kullback-Leibler divergence loss term.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Food Taste Similarity Prediction Based on Images and Human Judgments</title>
      <link>https://tutunarsl.github.io/project/eth-iml-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tutunarsl.github.io/project/eth-iml-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;description&#34;&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A dataset of images of 10,000 dishes, together with a set of triplets representing human annotations of food taste similarity is provided. The objective of the project is to predict for unseen triplets $(A, B, C)$, whether dish $A$ is more similar in taste to $B$ or $C$. In this project, image embeddings are learned through an autoencoder, where the loss is computed based on distances between the embeddings.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Medical Events Prediction with Missing Features and Imbalanced Classification</title>
      <link>https://tutunarsl.github.io/project/eth-iml-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tutunarsl.github.io/project/eth-iml-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;description&#34;&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Patients in hospitals are often continuously monitored by the medical personnel, who collect data about the patients&amp;rsquo; demographics, vital signs and lab test results. In this project, forecasts are made on the future occurrence of medical events such as sepsis, future orders of medical tests, as well as the evolution of key vital signs of patients in the remainder of their stay, based on data available from their first 12 recorded hours of stay. Accurate predictions could potentially help in resource planning and workflow management in hospitals. To address the challenges of missing features and imbalance classification, simple imputer, standard scaler, and histogram-based gradient boosting classification tree are used.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
